Brotherhood Wine Company Records, 1822-2006
Brotherhood Wine Company Records
- Series VII. Ledger Books (Box 8, 9, 10, 11, 12)
  Ledger books of various sizes containing financial statements, budgets, employee pay, income, trial balances, sales, expenses, shipping logs, etc.
  Ledgers are in chronologic order as found on the guide. Since the ledgers are all similar please replace them in the box in the same order so that they can be identified easily in the future. Each ledger has a strip of paper on the inside cover that lists the title as found on the guide. Fragile and dirty. Handle with care. Apron advised.
  - Minute book (orange red leather), 1900-1922 (Box 9)
    Includes meeting minutes of the Board of Directors, stockholder meetings, by laws, official documents.
  - Check ledger, expenses (Orange and red leather), September 1914 - February 1920 (Box 9)
  - Incomplete alphabetic ledger (No covers), 1916-1924 (Box 9)
    Includes cask capacities and gallons of types of wine stored.
  - Sales record (Large, metal bindings, cover says Sales Record), December 1917 - October 1920 (Box 9)
  - Cash record (Large, metal bindings, cover says Cash Record), June 1918 - August 1922 (Box 9)
  - Alphabetic ledger (orange red leather), 1920-1936 (Box 9)
    Includes sales receipts, expenses by subject, cash, accounts receivable, interest, cooperage, etc.
  - Company finances ledger (Cover has sticker that says Brotherhood Corporation February 1920), February 1920 - July 1925 (Box 10)
  - Ledger book (Cover has a sticker that says Trial Balance), February 1920 - January 1927 (Box 10)
  - Sales ledger (Black, faded yellow sticker on the cover), June 1921 - September 1929 (Box 10)
    Sales figures for House, J. W. Flanagan, J. A. Alexanderson, H. F. Flanagan, and others.
  - Incomplete ledger (Dirty black and red sticker on cover, covers not attached), 1923-1934 (Box 10)
    Includes information on wine, empty barrels, and kegs returned, and has some order in the back.
  - Company finances ledger (Black, remains of a sticker on the cover), February 1927 - July 1932 (Box 10)
  - Sales ledger (Black, cover has a sticker that says Brotherhood Corporation), October 1929 - December 1937 (Box 10)
    Sales figures for House, J.W.F, J.A.A., C.F.F., and M+M.
  - Ledger book, in part for a movie theater, 1930-1933 (Box 10)
    Has financial, bank checking, information from employees including L. L. Farrell. Some information about wine and kegs returned. A large portion appears to be a movie theater ledger book. Lists income and expenses from movie titles with lists of features shown. Also expenses from movie sound equipment. Includes a brief description of what type of movie each was and which studio produced it, Columbia, Metro, etc.
  - Order account book (Grey, design on cover, loose binding), March 1931 - November 1934 (Box 10)
    Includes names and addresses of accounts. Some laid in order correspondence.
  - Time book (Black and red, says Time Book on cover), November 1933 - September 1936 (Box 10)
    Includes employee hours worked and wages paid.
  - Ledger book (Black says JOURNAL on the spine), December 1934 - October 1945 (Box 10)
  - Alphabetic ledger (Black, poor shape, cover not attached), 1935 - 1948 (Box 11)
    Cash, sales receipts, expenses by subject.
  - Diary (Small, red, cover says Daily Reminder 1936), 1936 (Box 12)
    Includes bank balances, payroll, payments.
  - Cash ledger (Large, black and red), June 1937 - June 1939 (Box 12)
  - Diary (Small, black, cover says Diary 1938), 1938 (Box 12)
  - Ledger (Says Journal in gold on red spine), January 1938 - August 1948 (Box 11)
  - Disbursements (Poor condition, black and red), June 1939 - May 1948 (Box 11)
  - Sales ledger and 1960s Scrapbook, October 1939 - August 1944, 1962-1967 (Box 8)
  - Check register (Says Journal in black on red spine, faded black and red), December 1939 - September 1942 (Box 11)
  - Diary (Small green, cover says Continental Diary 1941), 1941 (Box 12)
  - Sales ledger (Small black, cover says Journal), May 1945 - July 1949 (Box 12)
  - Income ledger (Large, black and red), December 1946 - February 1950 (Box 12)
  - Guest book (Spine says Club Register), 1950-1953 (Box 11)
  - Guest Book Register (Small blue), 1953 -1956 (Box 11)
  - Cash disbursements (Black and red), April 1953 - January 1956 (Box 11)
  - Cash receipts (Black and red), March 1954 - October 1958 (Box 11)
  - Cash disbursements, some loose material in back (Black and red), February 1956 - December 1958 (Box 11)
  - Sherry ledger (metal hinge clasp), 1974 - 1977 (Box 11)